<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  
  <!-- EN: baseliner -->
  <Baseliner.label>dasar</Baseliner.label>
  <!-- EN: A naturally-evolved human with no major significant genetic modifications. -->
  <Baseliner.description>Manusia yang telah berevolusi secara alami tanpa modifikasi genetik yang hebat.</Baseliner.description>
  
  <!-- EN: dirtmole -->
  <Dirtmole.label>dot</Dirtmole.label>
  <!-- EN: With gray skin adapted to artificial light, they thrive in cramped and dark spaces where combat and travel happen over short distances. They are extremely capable at digging or mining tasks. In the open, however, they suffer from a sensitivity to light, slow speed and poor eyesight at distance.\n\nAfter the first tunnel colonies failed due to the stress of confinement, colonization agencies began genetically altering colonists to live without open space or sunlight. This xenotype is known colloquially as the dirtmoles. Today, dirtmoles have expanded out of their original tunnel homes and rule many confined spaces in the anthrosphere. They can be found in deep mines, cramped low-tech spacecraft, and teeming by the billions in the dark underlayers of countless urbworlds. -->
  <Dirtmole.description>Dengan kulit abu -abu diadaptasi dengan cahaya buatan, mereka berkembang di ruang sempit dan gelap di mana pertempuran dan perpindahan terjadi pada jarak pendek.Mereka sangat mampu melakukan penggalian atau tugas penambangan. Namun, di lapangan terbuka, mereka menderita sensitivitas cahaya, kelambatan dan penglihatan jarak yang buruk.Xenotype ini secara sehari -hari dikenal sebagai tapo Bumi.Saat ini, Terra-Topos telah berkembang di luar rumah asli mereka di terowongan dan mendominasi banyak ruang yang terkurung di antrop.Mereka dapat ditemukan di tambang yang dalam, di pesawat ruang angkasa teknologi rendah dan berkerumun untuk miliaran di lapisan bawah tanah gelap dunia kota yang tak terhitung banyaknya.</Dirtmole.description>
  <!-- EN: With gray skin adapted to artificial light, dirtmoles thrive in cramped and dark spaces where combat and travel happen over short distances. They are naturals at digging and navigating complex tunnel structures. In the open, they suffer from a sensitivity to light, slow speed and poor eyesight at distance. -->
  <Dirtmole.descriptionShort>Dengan kulit abu-abu diadaptasi dengan cahaya buatan, terra-topos tumbuh subur di ruang sempit dan gelap di mana pertempuran dan perjalanan terjadi pada jarak pendek.Mereka adalah ahli dalam penggalian dan konstruksi terowongan yang kompleks.Di lapangan terbuka, mereka menderita sensitivitas cahaya, kelambatan dan pandangan yang buruk.</Dirtmole.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: genie -->
  <Genie.label>jenius</Genie.label>
  <!-- EN: Designed to be engineers, genies' delicate bones and natural aptitude with machines allow them to manipulate devices with remarkable precision. They are emotionally cold and can follow orders where others might panic. However, they are fragile, and their amplified nerve impulses make them easy to debilitate with relatively little pain. With so much of their brains dedicated to analyzing machines, they lack the neural hardware to analyze emotions, so they sometimes come off as socially inept. Their dead calm makes it even harder for them to relate to what they see as madly-hotheaded baseliner humans.\n\nGenies were engineered thousands of years ago by a long-disbanded space navy to hold engineering positions on large starships. Today, genies still serve as engineers in great cities and fleets, but many can also be found working as lawyers, pilots, and musicians. -->
  <Genie.description>Dirancang untuk menjadi insinyur, tulang -tulang halus para jenius dan bakat alami mereka dengan mesin memungkinkan mereka untuk memanipulasi perangkat dengan presisi yang luar biasa.Mereka secara emosional dingin dan dapat mengikuti perintah di mana orang lain bisa panik.Namun, mereka rapuh dan impuls saraf yang diperkuat membuatnya mudah dilemahkan dengan rasa sakit yang relatif sedikit.Dengan mendedikasikan sebagian besar otaknya untuk analisis mesin, mereka tidak memiliki perangkat keras saraf untuk menganalisis emosi, jadi kadang -kadang mereka tidak kompeten secara sosial.Ketenangannya yang mutlak membuat mereka semakin sulit untuk berhubungan dengan apa yang mereka lihat sebagai manusia dasar yang sangat ditinggikan.Saat ini, para genius terus bekerja sebagai insinyur di kota -kota besar dan armada, tetapi banyak yang juga dapat bekerja sebagai pengacara, pilot, dan musisi.</Genie.description>
  <!-- EN: Designed to be engineers, genies have natural aptitude with machines, and are emotionally cold and calm. They are also fragile and vulnerable to pain. Focused on machines, they often come off as socially inept. -->
  <Genie.descriptionShort>Dirancang untuk menjadi insinyur, para jenius memiliki keterampilan alami dengan mesin dan secara emosional dingin dan tenang.Mereka juga rapuh dan rentan terhadap rasa sakit.Mesin centering, mereka biasanya tidak kompeten secara sosial.</Genie.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: highmate -->
  <Highmate.label>adalah</Highmate.label>
  <!-- EN: Designed companions and concubines with a unique ability to psychically bond with a mate, highmates are empathic, beautiful, cheerful, and talented in social matters. They are also inept at manual tasks, physically weak, and mentally incapable of violence.\n\nOn a few wealthy worlds, highmate xenogerms are commercially available and some people become highmates as a sort of career. However, many societies find them abhorrent, either because they distract people from forming natural families, or because they are humans shaped to serve the pleasures of another. On such worlds they are either reserved as playthings of the powerful, or banned entirely. This particular line of highmate fits the fashions of classical Novaroma, but many other variants exist. -->
  <Highmate.description>Dirancang sebagai kolega dan selir dengan kemampuan unik untuk secara psikis terhubung dengan pasangan, succubes adalah empatik, cantik, ceria dan berbakat untuk masalah sosial.Mereka juga tidak kompeten untuk manual, lemah secara fisik dan secara mental tidak dapat melakukan kekerasan.Namun, banyak masyarakat menganggap mereka menjijikkan, baik karena mereka mengalihkan perhatian orang dari pembentukan keluarga alami, atau karena mereka adalah manusia yang berbentuk untuk melayani kesenangan orang lain.Di dunia ini mereka dicadangkan sebagai mainan yang kuat atau sepenuhnya dilarang.Garis succubes khusus ini sesuai dengan mode novaroma klasik, tetapi ada banyak varian lainnya.</Highmate.description>
  <!-- EN: Designed companions and concubines with a unique ability to psychically bond with a mate, highmates are empathic, beautiful, cheerful, and talented in social matters. They are also inept at manual tasks, physically weak, and mentally incapable of violence. -->
  <Highmate.descriptionShort>Dirancang sebagai kolega dan selir dengan kemampuan unik untuk secara psikis terhubung dengan pasangan, succubes adalah empatik, cantik, ceria dan berbakat untuk masalah sosial.Mereka juga tidak kompeten untuk tugas -tugas manual, secara fisik lemah dan secara mental tidak dapat melakukan kekerasan.</Highmate.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: hussar -->
  <Hussar.label>bangunan</Hussar.label>
  <!-- EN: Hussars are engineered soldiers. They fight aggressively and with precision, heal fast, thrive in extreme temperatures, and freely ingest military drugs. They have a genetic dependence on go-juice, which also makes them less likely to rebel against their commanders.\n\nWhile hussars' emotions make them dangerous in combat, they can't relate to baseliner humans. They are famous for their blood-red eyes and "hussar stare", a dead expression that unsettles many people. Their lack of expression and burning aggressive nature has led to many violent misunderstandings.\n\nIn most societies where they live, hussars are kept separated from the rest of the population. Hussars are single-purpose tools - and they generally aren't bothered by the fact. -->
  <Hussar.description>Húsar adalah tentara yang dirancang oleh insinyur.Mereka bertarung dengan agresivitas dan ketepatan, mereka sembuh dengan cepat, berkembang dalam suhu ekstrem dan menelan obat militer secara bebas.Mereka memiliki ketergantungan genetik pada neurozumo, yang membuat mereka lebih kecil kemungkinannya untuk memberontak terhadap komandan mereka.Mereka terkenal karena mata merah mereka seperti darah dan "penampilan hussar" mereka, ekspresi mati yang mengkhawatirkan banyak orang.Kurangnya ekspresi dan sifat agresifnya yang membakar telah menyebabkan banyak kesalahpahaman kekerasan.Hussar adalah satu alat yang digunakan, dan fakta ini umumnya tidak mengganggu mereka.</Hussar.description>
  <!-- EN: Hussars are engineered soldiers. They fight aggressively and with precision, heal fast, thrive in extreme temperatures, and freely ingest military drugs. They have a genetic dependence on go-juice. -->
  <Hussar.descriptionShort>Hussars adalah tentara yang dirancang oleh insinyur.Mereka bertarung dengan agresivitas dan ketepatan, mereka sembuh dengan cepat, berkembang dalam suhu ekstrem dan menelan obat militer secara bebas.Mereka memiliki ketergantungan genetik pada neurozumo.</Hussar.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: impid -->
  <Impid.label>Diablillo</Impid.label>
  <!-- EN: Made for desert life, impid cultures live on many rimworlds and dry deathworlds. Impids are extremely fast-moving, easily tolerate high temperatures, and can spew fire from their mouths. Though they are masters on the sand, impids struggle in other environments. They are terrible with farming. They fight well at range, but in close combat their physical weakness becomes apparent.\n\nOutlanders call them dustrunners because of their speed over open terrain and resistance to heat. Some tribes call them devils because of their horns and because they burn their enemies. Impid tribes' combat tactics usually center on rapid-approach incendiary attacks using both handheld fire weapons and their fire spew ability. -->
  <Impid.description>Fakta seumur hidup di padang pasir, budaya Diablillo hidup di banyak dunia perbatasan dan dunia mati.Ikatnya sangat cepat, mudah mentolerir suhu tinggi dan dapat meludahkan tembakan melalui mulut.Meskipun mereka adalah guru di arena, gangguan mengalami kesulitan di lingkungan lain.Mereka mengerikan dengan pertanian. Mereka bertarung dengan baik di kejauhan, tetapi dalam jarak dekat memerangi kelemahan fisik mereka hadir.Beberapa suku menyebut mereka setan untuk tanduk mereka dan karena mereka membakar musuh mereka.Taktik tempur dari suku -suku impian sering fokus pada serangan pendekatan cepat menggunakan tangan dan kemampuan mereka untuk meludahkan api.</Impid.description>
  <!-- EN: Made for desert life, impids are very fast, can spew fire from their mouths, and easily tolerate high temperatures. They fight well at range, but in close combat they do little damage. They are terrible with farming, and have weak immune systems. -->
  <Impid.descriptionShort>Dibuat untuk kehidupan di padang pasir, menyiratkan sangat cepat, mereka dapat meludahkan api di mulut dan dengan mudah mentolerir suhu tinggi.Mereka bertarung dengan baik di kejauhan, tetapi dalam pertempuran jarak dekat mereka melakukan sedikit kerusakan.Mereka mengerikan dengan pertanian dan memiliki sistem kekebalan tubuh yang lemah.</Impid.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: neanderthal -->
  <Neanderthal.label>Neanderthal</Neanderthal.label>
  <!-- EN: Neanderthals are stocky, powerfully-built humanoids. Their most salient characteristic is that they are difficult to hurt: They are very resistant to injury, and their strong immune systems protect them from infection. However, without ever having evolved in a complex civilization, they are less adept than baseliner humans at intellectual and social tasks, and their impulsiveness can make them dangerously aggressive.\n\nHomo neanderthalensis was originally an archaic population of hominids that emerged over 200,000 years ago during the Pleistocene epoch. After they were replaced by and merged with humans 30,000 years ago, they were absent for tens of thousands of years until scientists resurrected them from ancient DNA. Neanderthals now survive in sub-societies on some settled planets. On the rimworlds, neanderthal tribes carve out the same existence as their Earth ancestors did so long ago. -->
  <Neanderthal.description>Neanderthal adalah humanoids fornid dan kompleks yang kuat.Karakteristik mereka yang paling menonjol adalah bahwa mereka sulit untuk terluka: mereka sangat tahan terhadap cedera dan sistem kekebalan tubuh yang kuat melindungi mereka dari infeksi.Namun, setelah tidak pernah berevolusi menuju peradaban yang kompleks, mereka kurang terampil daripada manusia dasar dalam tugas intelektual dan sosial, dan impulsif mereka dapat membuat mereka agresif berbahaya.Setelah digantikan oleh manusia dan menggabungkan dengan mereka 30.000 tahun yang lalu, mereka absen selama puluhan ribu tahun sampai para ilmuwan membangkitkan mereka dari DNA lama.Saat ini, Neanderthal bertahan hidup dalam subsoksi di beberapa planet yang diselesaikan.Di dunia perbatasan, suku -suku Neanderthal mencari nafkah seperti yang dilakukan oleh leluhur terestrial mereka.</Neanderthal.description>
  <!-- EN: Neanderthals are stocky, powerfully-built humanoids. They are hardy and difficult to injure, and their strong immune systems protect them from infection. However, their minds are less adept at intellectual and social tasks, and their impulsiveness can make them dangerously aggressive. -->
  <Neanderthal.descriptionShort>Neanderthal adalah humanoids fornid dan kompleks yang kuat.Mereka resisten dan sulit untuk dilukai, dan sistem kekebalan tubuh mereka yang kuat melindungi mereka dari infeksi.Namun, pikiran mereka kurang terampil dalam tugas intelektual dan sosial, dan impulsif mereka dapat membuat mereka sangat agresif.</Neanderthal.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: pigskin -->
  <Pigskin.label>Skincard</Pigskin.label>
  <!-- EN: Pigskins are human-pig hybrids which are capable of two-legged movement, tool use, and speech, but which also retain many pig-like qualities. They are hardy and can eat almost anything without getting sick, but their trotter-shaped hands leave them at a disadvantage when attempting to precisely manipulate tools and objects. They don't see well at a distance, so pigskin gangs usually focus on close-range weapons. They also have a strong taste for explosives.\n\nPigskins were made for their organs. Uncomfortable with the idea of harvesting organs from baseliner humans, a long-gone government merged human DNA into pigs to make the animals produce more easily-transplantable hearts and lungs. They succeeded, but the resulting creatures became more humanlike than anyone anticipated. -->
  <Pigskin.description>Kulitnya adalah hibrida jam manusia yang mampu pindah ke dua kaki, menggunakan alat dan berbicara, tetapi juga mempertahankan banyak kualitas babi.Mereka tahan dan bisa makan hampir semua hal tanpa sakit, tetapi lubang mereka berbentuk seperti kerugian ketika mereka mencoba memanipulasi alat dan benda secara akurat.Mereka tidak melihat dengan baik di kejauhan, jadi band babi biasanya fokus pada senjata pendek -pendek.Mereka juga memiliki selera yang bagus untuk bahan peledak. \ N \ nlos skles diciptakan oleh organ mereka.Tidak nyaman dengan gagasan mengekstraksi organ dari manusia dasar, pemerintah kuno menggabungkan DNA manusia pada babi sehingga hewan menghasilkan hati dan paru -paru lebih mudah ditransplantasikan.Mereka mendapatkannya, tetapi makhluk yang dihasilkan lebih mirip manusia daripada yang diharapkan siapa pun.</Pigskin.description>
  <!-- EN: Pigskins are human-pig hybrids. They are hardy and can eat almost anything without getting sick, but their trotter-shaped hands are bad at fine manipulation. They don't see well at a distance, so they usually focus on close-range weapons. They have a strong taste for explosives. -->
  <Pigskin.descriptionShort>Kulitnya adalah hibrida manusia dan babi.Mereka tahan dan bisa makan hampir semua hal tanpa sakit, tetapi lubang mereka berbentuk seperti lubang buruk untuk manipulasi yang baik.Mereka tidak melihat dengan baik di kejauhan, jadi mereka biasanya fokus pada senjata pendek pendek.Mereka memiliki selera yang bagus untuk bahan peledak.</Pigskin.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: sanguophage -->
  <Sanguophage.label>darah</Sanguophage.label>
  <!-- EN: Sanguophages are a type of archotech-enhanced xenohuman. Powered by archites, their abilities go far beyond normal genetic enhancements. They are mentally adept and preternaturally beautiful. In combat, they can launch deadly spines and heal injured friends. They don't age or die naturally and never suffer from disease or poison. A sanguophage can make a new sanguophage by reimplanting their own xenogerm into a person.\n\nSanguophages must regularly consume hemogen derived from human blood, and they must periodically deathrest for long periods. They're easily destroyed by fire, and slowed down by UV light.\n\nThe first sanguophage appeared thousands of years ago when the lord-explorer Varan-Dur sought to control a hyperintelligent archotech and found himself transformed by it instead. Every sanguophage is descended from him. Since then, sanguophages have often been hunted because of their destabilizing power and their need for blood. Since they can pass for baseliners, many live in hiding among typical humans.\n\nTheir numbers are unknown. Some think they are legends or rare irrelevancies. Some believe sanguophages secretly direct entire human civilizations. The stories speak of eternal lords ruling billions from slate-black space stations, or directing blood sacrifices at conferences in the underlayers of the deepest urbworlds. -->
  <Sanguophage.description>Sanguifagos adalah jenis xenohumans yang ditingkatkan secara arkeoteknologis.Didorong oleh Architas, keterampilan mereka jauh melampaui perbaikan genetik normal.Mereka terampil secara mental dan keindahan supernatural.Dalam pertempuran, mereka dapat meluncurkan duri fana dan menyembuhkan teman -teman mereka yang terluka. Mereka tidak menua atau mati secara alami dan tidak pernah menderita penyakit atau racun.Berdarah dapat menciptakan darah baru yang menata ulang xenogermennya sendiri pada seseorang. Mereka mudah dihancurkan oleh api, dan diperlambat oleh sinar ultraviolet.Semua berdarah turun darinya.Sejak itu, orang berdarah sering dianiaya oleh kekuatan destabilisasi mereka dan kebutuhan mereka akan darah.Seperti yang bisa menjadi dasar, banyak yang hidup tersembunyi di antara manusia yang khas. Nomor \ nsu tidak diketahui.Beberapa percaya mereka adalah legenda atau tidak relevan.Beberapa percaya bahwa berdarah langsung mengarahkan seluruh peradaban manusia.Kisah -kisah berbicara tentang para penguasa abadi yang mengatur miliaran orang dari stasiun hitam papan tulis, atau yang mengarahkan pengorbanan darah dalam konferensi di lapisan tanah dunia perkotaan terdalam.</Sanguophage.description>
  <!-- EN: Sanguophages are ageless, deathless super-humans powered by archotech-created archites in the bloodstream. They are beautiful and extremely intelligent. They can heal any injury, and never suffer from disease or poison. In combat, they can launch deadly spines and heal injured friends. The price is that sanguophages must consume hemogen derived from human blood to survive, and they must periodically deathrest for long periods. They're easily destroyed by fire, and slowed down by UV light. -->
  <Sanguophage.descriptionShort>Yang berdarah adalah manusia super abadi dan abadi, didorong oleh arsitek yang diciptakan oleh arkeoteknologi dalam aliran darah.Mereka cantik dan sangat cerdas.Mereka dapat menyembuhkan luka apa pun dan tidak pernah menderita penyakit atau racun.Dalam pertempuran, mereka dapat meluncurkan duri fana dan menyembuhkan teman -teman mereka yang terluka.Harganya adalah bahwa berdarah harus mengonsumsi hemogen yang berasal dari darah manusia untuk bertahan hidup, dan harus dipasang secara teratur untuk waktu yang lama.Mereka mudah dihancurkan oleh api dan diperlambat oleh sinar ultraviolet.</Sanguophage.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: waster -->
  <Waster.label>terak</Waster.label>
  <!-- EN: Wasters are aggressive, immune to toxic pollution, almost impervious to disease, and can ingest as much psychite and wake-up drugs as they wish with no ill effects. Their toxin-adapted metabolism means they must consume some form of psychite - usually flake or yayo.\n\nOriginally engineered to prevent resettlement of post-apocalyptic deathworlds, wasters are living area-denial weapons. Waster pirates armed with toxic weapons are the bane of many frontier peoples, both on the rimworlds and in the depths of the urbworld hyperstructures. -->
  <Waster.description>Terak itu agresif, kebal terhadap polusi beracun, hampir tidak sensitif terhadap penyakit, dan dapat menelan sebanyak mungkin psikit dan obat -obatan untuk dibangunkan seperti yang mereka inginkan tanpa efek negatif.Metabolisme yang disesuaikan dengan racun berarti mereka harus mengkonsumsi beberapa bentuk psikit, biasanya skala atau yayo.Bajak laut sampah, yang dipersenjatai dengan senjata beracun, adalah kebinasaan banyak kota perbatasan, baik di dunia perbatasan maupun di kedalaman hiperstruktur dunia kota.</Waster.description>
  <!-- EN: Wasters are aggressive, immune to toxic pollution, almost impervious to disease, and can ingest as much psychite and wake-up drugs as they wish with no ill effects. Their toxin-adapted metabolism means they must consume some form of psychite - usually flake or yayo. -->
  <Waster.descriptionShort>Terak itu agresif, kebal terhadap polusi beracun, hampir tidak sensitif terhadap penyakit, dan dapat menelan sebanyak mungkin psikit dan obat -obatan untuk dibangunkan seperti yang mereka inginkan tanpa efek negatif.Metabolisme yang disesuaikan dengan racun berarti mereka harus mengkonsumsi beberapa bentuk psikit, biasanya skala atau yayo.</Waster.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: yttakin -->
  <Yttakin.label>yt</Yttakin.label>
  <!-- EN: Yttakin descend from colonists engineered to thrive on ultra-cold planets. Their great size and fur make them hardy in frozen environments. Yttakin share a psychic connection with the wildlife and can summon animals to their side during battles. They are not fast or energetic or precise, but can keep going when others would have collapsed long before.\n\nSince they migrated off their icy birthworld of Yttak, Yttakin settlements live on many planets. Their fur, roaring voices, and aversion to urban living sometimes leads naive outsiders to believe they are simple-minded animals. Quick-minded Yttakin are happy to make good use of such wrong beliefs, whether at the negotiating table or on the battlefield. -->
  <Yttakin.description>Yttakin turun dari pemukim yang dirancang untuk makmur di planet ultra -Afrika.Ukuran dan bulu mereka yang besar membuat mereka tahan di lingkungan es krim.Yttakin berbagi hubungan psikis dengan fauna dan dapat memanggil hewan di sisi mereka selama pertempuran.Mereka tidak cepat atau energik atau tepat, tetapi mereka dapat melanjutkan ketika orang lain akan runtuh jauh lebih awal.Bulu -Nya, suaranya yang menderu dan keengganannya terhadap kehidupan perkotaan membuat orang asing yang naif menciptakan kadang -kadang mereka adalah hewan pikiran sederhana.Yttakin, dengan cepat, dengan senang hati memanfaatkan keyakinan yang salah ini, baik di meja perundingan atau di medan perang.</Yttakin.description>
  <!-- EN: Yttakin descend from colonists engineered to thrive on ultra-cold planets. Their great size and fur make them hardy in frozen environments, and they have a unique ability to communicate vocally and psychically with animals. They are not fast or energetic or precise, but can keep going when others would have collapsed long before. -->
  <Yttakin.descriptionShort>Yttakin turun dari pemukim yang dirancang untuk makmur di planet ultra -Afrika.Ukuran dan bulu mereka yang besar membuat mereka tahan di lingkungan es krim, dan memiliki kemampuan unik untuk berkomunikasi vokal dan secara psikis dengan hewan.Mereka tidak cepat atau energik atau tepat, tetapi mereka dapat melanjutkan ketika orang lain akan runtuh jauh lebih awal.</Yttakin.descriptionShort>
  
</LanguageData>